<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CV on Xu Liu</title>
    <link>https://xliusufe.github.io/categories/cv/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CV on Xu Liu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-CN</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 21:29:44 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://xliusufe.github.io/categories/cv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Biography</title>
      <link>https://xliusufe.github.io/post/cv/biography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 21:29:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xliusufe.github.io/post/cv/biography/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to myself Xu Liu is currently an Associate Professor in the School of Statistics and Management at Shanghai University of Finance and Economics. He received Ph.D. in Statistics at Yunnan University in January 2011. Xu was an NSF postdoctoral fellow in the Department of Statistics at Northwestern University during 2011-2013, and in the Department of Statistics and Probablity at Michigan State University during 2013-2016. His current research interests include</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grants</title>
      <link>https://xliusufe.github.io/post/cv/grants/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 21:29:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xliusufe.github.io/post/cv/grants/</guid>
      <description>Grants &amp;ldquo;Semiparametric modelling and statistical inference for gene data of complex disease&amp;rdquo; (NSF of China, 11771267), PI Date of project: January/01/2018 - December/31/2021 &amp;ldquo;High-dimensional statistical inference incorporating complex networks and its applications in genomic data&amp;rdquo; (NSF of China, 12271329), PI Date of project: January/01/2023 - December/31/2026 Homepage go back to go back to</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://xliusufe.github.io/post/cv/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 21:29:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xliusufe.github.io/post/cv/publications/</guid>
      <description>Published Papers ($\color{red}{\small{*corresponding author,\underline{trainee}}} $) Zhang, X., Liu, X., and Shi X.* (2023). Model Selection for Varying Coefficient Nonparametric Transformation Model. The Econometrics Journal. Published online. DOI:10.1093/ectj/utad007. An R-package &amp;ldquo;GFabs&amp;rdquo; is available at https://github.com/xliusufe/GFabs. Zhang, X., Shi X.*, Liu, Y., Liu, X., and Ma, S. (2023). A general framework for identifying hierarchical interactions and its application to genomics data. Journal of Computational and Graphical Statistics. Published online. DOI:10.1080/10618600.2022.2152034. An R-package</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://xliusufe.github.io/post/cv/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 21:29:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xliusufe.github.io/post/cv/resume/</guid>
      <description>Contact Information Tel: (+86) 021-6590-1156 Email: liu.xu@sufe.edu.cn Address: No. 777, Guoding Rd., Shanghai 200433, China School of Statistics and Management (Rm. 2207), Shanghai University of Finance and Economics (SUFE), Education 2011 received Ph.D. in Statistics, Yunnan University Work Experience 08/2022 - Present, Tenured Associate Professor, School of Statistics and Management, SUFE, 07/2019 - 06/2022, Associate Professor, School of Statistics and Management, SUFE, 06/2016 - 06/2019, Assistant Professor, School of Statistics</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Softwares</title>
      <link>https://xliusufe.github.io/post/cv/softwares/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 21:29:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xliusufe.github.io/post/cv/softwares/</guid>
      <description>R packages The Python codes &amp;ldquo;REGS&amp;rdquo; is proposed for sampling from unnormalized densties by the techniques including Wasserstein gradient flows, numerical ODEs, density-ratio estimation and deep neural networks. REGS achieves a fantastic numerical performance on 2D mixtrues of Gaussian distributions with a large number of modes, a small variance, and a large distance between any two modes. &amp;ldquo;REGS&amp;rdquo; is available at https://github.com/xliusufe/REGS. Refer to Feng X., Gao, Y., Huang, J.,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://xliusufe.github.io/post/cv/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 21:29:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xliusufe.github.io/post/cv/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Shanghai University of Finance and Economics STT102480: Mathematical Statistics Spring 2017 Spring 2018 Spring 2021 Spring 2022 STT311240: Advanced Mathematical Statistics Fall 2016 Fall 2017 Fall 2018 Fall 2019 Fall 2020 STT213488: Data analysis and statistical modeling Fall 2017 Fall 2018 Fall 2019 Fall 2020 Fall 2021 Fall 2022 STT101828: Computer Programming (C/C++) Spring 2019 Spring 2020 Spring 2023 STT310537: Topics on High-dimensional Data Spring 2017 Spring 2018 Fall 2019</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trainee</title>
      <link>https://xliusufe.github.io/post/cv/trainees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 21:29:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xliusufe.github.io/post/cv/trainees/</guid>
      <description>PhD Students Yiming Liu received her PhD degree in 2023. His thesis title is &amp;ldquo;Multi-task Learning for High-dimensional Multi-view Data via Tensor Estimation&amp;rdquo;. She is currently Xiao Zhang received his PhD degree in 2021. His thesis title is &amp;ldquo;Variable Selection and Inference for High Dimensional Data&amp;rdquo;. He is currently a postdoc in the Centre for Quantitative Medicine at Duke-NUS Medical School, Singapore. Xiangyong Tan received his PhD degree in 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>